The coast is toast.
Volcano is a science fiction, action, drama film directed by Mick Jackson.
An earthquake shatters a peaceful Los Angeles morning and opens a fissure
deep into the earth, causing lava to start bubbling up.
As a volcano begins forming in the La Brea Tar Pits, the director of the city's emergency management service, working
with a geologist, must then use every resource in the city to try and stop the volcano from consuming LA.
Mike Roark, played by Tommy Lee Jones.
Dr. Amy Barnes, played by Anne Heche.
Kelly Roark, played by Gaby Hoffmann.
Emmit Reese, played by Don Cheadle.
Dr. Jaye Calder, played by Jacqueline Kim.
Lt. Ed Fox, played by Keith David.
Volcano is a 1997 American disaster film directed by Mick Jackson, written
by Jerome Armstrong and Billy Ray, and produced by Neal H.
Moritz and Andrew Z.
The film stars Tommy Lee Jones in the lead role, with
Anne Heche, Don Cheadle and Keith David.
It tells the story of an effort to divert the path of a dangerous lava flow through the streets
of Los Angeles following the formation of a volcano at the La Brea Tar Pits.
The story was inspired by the 1943 formation of the Parícutin volcano in Mexico.
Volcano was released by 20th Century Fox in the United States on April 25, 1997.
It received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $122.8
million worldwide on a $90 million budget.
The film explores themes of lava, subway, volcano, volcanology, burned alive.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.